<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aiden Haak</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/</link><description>Recent content on Aiden Haak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aidenhaak.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving to GitHub Pages</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2022/03/05/moving-to-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2022/03/05/moving-to-github-pages/</guid><description>Long time no post!
After having to do an OS reinstall and losing my old deploy script I found myself lamenting the fact this blog did not have an automated deployment. Fortunately Hugo makes it super easy to get up and running with GitHub pages. The fact that GitHub Pages is 100% free is just icing on the cake.
Now where to spend that $1.50 in AWS S3 monthly savings&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Setting Up An OpenTTD Server Part 2</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2021/01/29/setting-up-an-openttd-server-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2021/01/29/setting-up-an-openttd-server-part-2/</guid><description>I found myself wanting to scratch my OpenTTD itch again but I need to setup another server as I had long ago nuked the server for part one. Turns out that part one is (unsurprisngly) a bit out of date after five years and this time I wanted to dabble in some custom graphics or GRFs for my server.
For the first problem there is a an easy fix thanks to an OpenTTD docker image.</description></item><item><title>Moving To Hugo</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2019/06/29/moving-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2019/06/29/moving-to-hugo/</guid><description>I have just put the finishing touches on this site&amp;rsquo;s second migration &amp;ndash; this time from Jekyll to Hugo. I&amp;rsquo;d been planning on doing this migration for a while but the lack of SCSS/SASS support was holding me back. Then in August 2019 Hugo 0.43 happened and with it the introduction of Hugo Pipes and SCSS/SASS. So there was nothing holding me back (except for a lack of free time of course).</description></item><item><title>OpenVPN and Iptables</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2016/07/16/openvpn-and-iptables/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2016/07/16/openvpn-and-iptables/</guid><description>I recently setup an OpenVPN server, I mostly followed the fantastic Digital Ocean (DO) guide, however I ended up using iptables instead of ufw. Since setting up my iptables configuration correctly was probably the one thing that gave me the most trouble I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share.
I setup OpenVPN using a TUN adapter for my OpenVPN server because 1: that&amp;rsquo;s what the DO guide does and 2: I don&amp;rsquo;t plan to do any bridging.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up An OpenTTD Server</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2015/11/08/setting-up-an-openttd-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2015/11/08/setting-up-an-openttd-server/</guid><description>Update: Check out part two for a more up to date guide.
I recently setup an OpenTTD server and I thought I might document the steps I took to do so.
I choose to use a Digital Ocean (DO) to host my server since I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to try them out for some time. It also helps that their cheapest hosting option is rather cheap - only $5 per month. And since I don&amp;rsquo;t think OpenTTD will be particularily memory intensive I am fairly certain that the extra 512MB of RAM for the $10 per month DO droplet will be needed.</description></item><item><title>Leap Second</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2015/06/14/leap-second/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2015/06/14/leap-second/</guid><description>The next leap second is almost upon us! It is due to be added at the end of this month when at midnight June 30 2015 the clocks will be wound forward by one second. This occasional adjustement is to keep Coordinated Universal Time (UTC) within an acceptable margin of error (approximately 0.9s) of Earth&amp;rsquo;s rotational time AKA mean solar time.
As harmless as this sounds it is very much the opposite given the rise of computing applications requiring very precise time keeping, financial and scientific applications in particular.</description></item><item><title>Going Static</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2015/02/08/going-static/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2015/02/08/going-static/</guid><description>By now you may have noticed the new décor of my site - the even more observant of you may have also noticed that my blog has migrated from Wordpress to Jekyll.
Besides the fact that all the cool kids have been moving their blogs away from Wordpress, there were three main reasons for the switch:
The plethora of Wordpress and PHP related security vulnerabilities that are floating around these days.</description></item><item><title>Doomed Canon Printer</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/09/17/doomed-canon-printer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/09/17/doomed-canon-printer/</guid><description>Canon&amp;rsquo;s security vulnerability is another man&amp;rsquo;s challenge to run doom:
So what protection does Canon use to prevent a malicious person from providing a malicious firmware? In a nutshell - nothing, there is no signing (the correct way to do it) but it does have very weak encryption. I will go into the nuts and bolts of how I broke that later in this blog post.
So we can therefore create our own custom firmware and update anyone’s printer with a Trojan image which spies on the documents being printed or is used as a gateway into their network.</description></item><item><title>Elegance of Constraints</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/07/24/elegance-of-constraints/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/07/24/elegance-of-constraints/</guid><description>Stumbled across this transcript of an interview with the designer Charles Eames.
Mme. L. Amic: Does the creation of Design admit constraint?
Charles Eames: Design depends largely on constraints.
Mme. L. Amic: What constraints?
Charles Eames: The sum of all constraints. Here is one of the few effective keys to the design problem: the ability of the designer to recognize as many of the constraints as possible, his willingness and enthusiasm for working within these constraints.</description></item><item><title>Tech News Trends</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/07/01/tech-news-trends/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/07/01/tech-news-trends/</guid><description>Some interesting comparisons:
Kinda backs up where I tend to go for my tech news these days. Interesting food for thought regardless.</description></item><item><title>Stroustrup On C++</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/03/02/stroustrup-on-c-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/03/02/stroustrup-on-c-/</guid><description>Edit: Yep! This is definitely a case of Poe&amp;rsquo;s Law and this interview is a spoof.
An interview with the creator of C++ Bjarne Stroustrup done in 1998 for the IEEE Computer Magazine has recently came to my attention, however I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely convinced of it&amp;rsquo;s veracity. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt of particular interest:
Stroustrup: Well, one day, when I was sitting in my office, I thought of this little scheme, which would redress the balance a little.</description></item><item><title>Fun With Robots</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/02/25/fun-with-robots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/02/25/fun-with-robots/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit of fun recently poking around and looking at a few websites&amp;rsquo; robots.txt files. Yes, it has been an exciting past couple of days!
For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know, a robots.txt is a file that gives instructions to web robots AKA web spiders or crawlers (e.g. Google&amp;rsquo;s web crawler). These instructions tell, or more accurately suggest, where the robots can and cannot access and how often they can query your website among other things.</description></item><item><title>Nobody "Likes" Facebook</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/02/17/nobody-likes-facebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/02/17/nobody-likes-facebook/</guid><description>I recently saw this video the other day:
And it reminded me of Paul Graham&amp;rsquo;s comments about Yahoo:
By 1998, Yahoo was the beneficiary of a de facto Ponzi scheme. Investors were excited about the Internet. One reason they were excited was Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s revenue growth. So they invested in new Internet startups. The startups then used the money to buy ads on Yahoo to get traffic. Which caused yet more revenue growth for Yahoo, and further convinced investors the Internet was worth investing in.</description></item><item><title>Samsung Google Divorce?</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/02/06/samsung-google-divorce/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/02/06/samsung-google-divorce/</guid><description>With the recent sale of the remnants of Motorola Mobility to Lenovo Google has managed to at least salvage something from its expensive mistake. That is Google and Samsung kissing and making up with the recent cross patent licensing deal signed between the two companies.
While there has been talk of a Samsung-Google divorce in the past, it came to a head at the recent CES 2014 where Samsung unveiled its &amp;ldquo;Magazine UX&amp;rdquo; interface.</description></item><item><title>Responsive Youtube</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/01/29/responsive-youtube/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/01/29/responsive-youtube/</guid><description>So when I actually loaded my website on my phone I saw that my embedded Youtube videos weren&amp;rsquo;t resizing automatically - i.e. not responsive. Some quick Googling and one of the top results was a nice elegant solution via CSS. I pretty much just added a margin and it was good to go.
.video-container { position: relative; margin: 30px; padding-bottom: 50%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden; } .</description></item><item><title>Apple still being Apple</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/01/17/apple-still-being-apple/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/01/17/apple-still-being-apple/</guid><description>I know I&amp;rsquo;m late to the party but here&amp;rsquo;s Apple&amp;rsquo;s latest ad:
And here&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good write up about it. Definitely a risky ad and I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure Apple hit the mark here.</description></item><item><title>What Happened to Science Fiction?</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/01/13/what-happened-to-science-fiction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/01/13/what-happened-to-science-fiction/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a huge science fiction (SF) fan in all mediums - books, computer games, TV shows and movies. However, when I stop and take stock of the current state of SF landscape - I can only weep.
On the seldom occasion when I go to the book store I go through an emotional roller coaster of sadness and anger. Anger when I go to the SF section and notice that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even warrant its own section separate from Fantasy (yes they are similar but I&amp;rsquo;m still of the opinion that SF should have it&amp;rsquo;s own section).</description></item><item><title>A Dolphin’s Tale&amp;#58; The Story of GameCube</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/01/09/a-dolphins-tale#58-the-story-of-gamecube/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/01/09/a-dolphins-tale#58-the-story-of-gamecube/</guid><description>Amazing article about the GameCube.
&amp;ldquo;Microsoft is going after performance only, and does not understand that the game is played with software. A Nintendo is ultimately a toy. It is the most advanced machine for playing games, and it is totally different from the Microsoft product. It is just like trying to compare a sumo wrestler and pro-wrestler; they play by totally different rules. We do not consider Microsoft to be our competitor,&amp;rdquo; said Yamauchi.</description></item><item><title>Yet Another JavaScript Rant</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/01/03/yet-another-javascript-rant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2014/01/03/yet-another-javascript-rant/</guid><description>So I have recently given into the hype and I&amp;rsquo;ve begun playing around with JavaScript a bit more lately. And yes I know there are already many many rants about it if you look hard enough. So I obviously thought to add my thoughts to the opinion soup.
There are two main problems I have with JavaScript. My first beef is that JavaScript as a language is loose - very loose.</description></item><item><title>Snapchat Security Disclosure</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2013/12/28/snapchat-security-disclosure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2013/12/28/snapchat-security-disclosure/</guid><description>Given the latest update to the GibSec Snapchat API:
Using our Snapchat API implementation, someone could save media sent to them, DoS Snapchat users, and as we recently found, build a database of Snapchat usernames and phone numbers, connecting names to aliases easily, and with further work connecting social media accounts to entries.
We also found that if someone was able to gain access to Snapchat&amp;rsquo;s servers, they could easily view, modify or replace snaps sent.</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2013/12/21/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/2013/12/21/hello-world/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m Aiden Haak and this my obligatory hello world post to launch my blog. I currently live in Australia and work as a software engineer. Thus most of my posts will deal with programming and technology as the norm.
Even though blogging could be dead (I&amp;rsquo;ve only missed the boat by almost 10 years) I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted at the very least my own website or blog. So that I could scrapbook my ideas and software projects over time.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.aidenhaak.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.aidenhaak.com/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m Aiden Haak, I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer and this is my blog.
It will mainly just be a hodge-podge collection of my various musings and ramblings, a bit of a scratch pad if you will. I might even occasionally post something almost interesting. Views entirely my own.
Thanks for reading!</description></item></channel></rss>